There may never be another dawn.
Legend is a adventure, fantasy film directed by Ridley Scott.
Set in a timeless mythical forest inhabited by fairies, goblins, unicorns and mortals, this fantastic
story follows a mystical forest dweller, chosen by fate, to undertake a heroic quest.
He must save the beautiful Princess  Lili and defeat the demonic Lord of
Darkness, or the world will be plunged into a never-ending ice age.
Jack, played by Tom Cruise.
Princess Lili, played by Mia Sara.
Lord of "Darkness", played by Tim Curry.
Honeythorn Gump, played by David Bennent.
Blix, played by Alice Playten.
Screwball, played by Billy Barty.
Legend is a 1985 American epic dark fantasy adventure film directed by Ridley Scott, written by William Hjortsberg, and starring
Tom Cruise, Mia Sara, Tim Curry, David Bennent, Alice Playten, Billy Barty, Cork Hubbert and Annabelle Lanyon.
The film revolves around Jack, a pure being who must stop the Lord of
Darkness who plots to cover the world with eternal night.
Despite its lack of commercial success and poor reception from critics, the film won the British Society of Cinematographers Award for Best Cinematography in 1985 for cinematographer Alex Thomson and was nominated for multiple awards: the Academy Award for Best Makeup; the
Academy of Science Fiction, Fantasy and Horror Films Saturn Award for Best Makeup; BAFTA Awards for Best Costume Design, Best Makeup Artist, and Best Special Visual Effects; DVD Exclusive Awards; and Youth in Film Awards (since renamed Young Artist Awards).
Since its premiere, reinforced by the 2002 release of the unrated
Director's Cut, the film has been called a cult classic.
The film explores themes of witch, princess, monster, magic, winter.
The tone is dark.